Preliminary Inventory of the György Barcza Nagyalásonyi Papers, 1911-1961
Hoover Institution Archives
György Barcza Nagyalásonyi Papers,
1911-1961
80030
Barcza Nagyalásonyi, György, 1888-1961
12 manuscript boxes (4.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Relates to Hungarian foreign relations, especially with the Vatican and Great Britain, the Hungarian entry into World War II, Hungarian diplomacy during the war, and secret negotations between Hungary and the Allied Powers in Switzerland, 1943-1945.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1980.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Form Available
Also available on microfilm (14 reels).
Access Points
World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Diplomatic history.; World War, 1939-1945--Hungary.; Great Britain.; Great Britain--Foreign relations--Hungary.; Hungary.; Hungary--Foreign relations--Great Britain.; Hungary--Foreign relations--Catholic Church.; Hungary--Foreign relations.; Catholic Church--Relations (diplomatic) with Hungary.; Diplomats--Hungary.
Container List
- MEMOIRS. Typescript (in Hungarian), 527 p. (Box 1)
- DIARIES (Box 2)
  - Bound
    - 1914-1918
    - 1923-1929 (diary for 1923 is incomplete and that for 1924 is missing) (Box 3)
    - 1930-1932 (Box 4)
    - 1933-1936 (Box 5)
    - 1941-1944 (first 181 pages of 1941 diary are missing) (Box 6)
    - 1945-1947 (Box 7)
  - Unbound
    - 1937
    - 1938-1940 (Box 8)
    - 1940 (Box 9)
- MEMOIRS
  - Volume I
    - First copy
    - Second copy (Box 10)
  - Volume II
    - London
    - Budapest
    - Switzerland (Box 11)
- CORRESPONDENCE
  - Teleki-Barcza, 1941
  - Hitler-Horthy
  - Barcza-Kallay/Bardossy
  - Re Hungarian Committee of Ministers
- MISCELLANY
  - Articles re activity of Antal Ullein-Reviczky (head of the Press Department of the Foreign Office during the Bardossy government)
  - Details from Barcza's memoirs and diaries
  - Press clippings re World War II, particularly collaborators and war criminals
  - Various original documents, World War I - World War II (Folder 11-12)